John Taggart Papers
John Taggart Papers
1965-1974
Taggart, John, 1942-
4 linear ft.
Papers of the American publisher, poet, editor of Maps. Correspondence and/or manuscripts relating to Maps by Paul Blackburn, George F. Butterick, Cid Corman, Robert Creeley, Robert Duncan, Theodore Enslin, Clayton Eshleman, Kathleen Fraser, Barbara Guest, Toby Olson, Steven Osterlund, Gary Snyder, Robert Vas Dias, Jonathan Williams, and others.
148695
Biographical History
John Taggart (1942- ) is an American experimental poet, essayist, and editor.
Born in Iowa, he received his BA from Earlham College, an MA from the University of Chicago, and a PhD from Syracuse University, where he wrote his dissertation on the poetry of Louis Zukofsky. He is the author of more than a dozen collections of poetry, and has been recognized many times for his work including a Pushcart Prize, the Chicago Review Poetry Prize, and two fellowships from the National Endowment for the Arts and one from the Ford Foundation.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John Taggart Papers consist of Correspondence, Memorabilia, and Writings. The Correspondence includes both personal and business letters, most of which relate to the publication of MAPS, a journal which Taggart edited. The Memorabilia comprises miscellaneous items of printed material, including an annotated copy of Walt Whitman's Poems. The Writings contain the editorial files and production records for the first six issues of MAPS. The editorial files feature the original manuscripts of the various contributors to the journal. Galleys, with extensive corrections by Editor Taggart and/or the authors themselves, constitute the journal's production records.
With the explanation, "One draws a map to show where one is," Taggart began publication of MAPS in 1966. The inaugural issue featured a Herbert Bayer cover, and included poetry by Paul Blackburn, Bobby Byrd, Russell Edson, Clayton Eshleman, Gabriel Heilig, Ken Irby, Murray Mednick, Nelson Richardson, Robert Vas Dias, Yorifumi Yaguchi, and Taggart himself. The subsequent issues appeared irregularly, and each centered on a particular person (sculptor David Smith #2, musician John Coltrane #3, and poets Charles Olson, Louis Zukofsky and Robert Duncan, #4-6 respectively). Through the mid-seventies contributors to the journal included Douglas Blazek, William Bronk, Cid Corman, Kenneth Cox, Guy Davenport, Larry Eigner, Theodore Enslin, Jaime Ferran, Barbara Guest, Michael Heller, Hugh Kenner, Joanne Kyger, Jackson Mac Low, Eric Mottram, John Newlove, Toby Olson, George Oppen, Steven Osterlund, and Charles Tomlinson.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender. Memorabilia and Writings are arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Bayer, Herbert, 1900-1985.; Bertholf, Robert J.; Blackburn, Paul.; Blackburn, Sara.; Blazek, Douglas, 1941-; Bly, Robert.; Boer, Charles, 1939-; Bowering, George, 1935-; Bronk, William.; Butterick, George F.; Byrd, Robert.; Carruth, Hayden, 1921-2008.; Coltrane, John, 1926-1967.; Corman, Cid.; Cornelius, Colin Jay.; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005.; Davenport, Guy.; Davey, Frank, 1940-; Davidson, Michael, 1944-; Duncan, Robert Edward, 1919-1988.; Economou, George.; Edson, Russell.; Eigner, Larry, 1927-1996.; Enslin, Theodore.; Eshleman, Clayton.; Ferrán, Jaime.; Ferrini, Vincent, 1913-2007.; Fowler, Gene, 1931-; Franks, David, 1948-; Fraser, Kathleen, 1935-; George, Jon.; Golden, Seán, 1948-; Goodell, Larry, 1935-; Grande, Félix, 1937-; Guest, Barbara.; Hall, Ted.; Heller, Michael, 1937-; Irby, Kenneth, 1936-; Jenkins, Donald.; Johnson, Ronald, 1935-1998.; Kenner, Hugh.; Kimberley, Nick.; Kostelanetz, Richard.; Kyger, Joanne.; La Belle, Christine.; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997.; Lekakis, Michael, 1907-1987.; Lenfest, David.; Lewis, Harry, 1942-; McNaughton, Duncan, 1942-; Mednick, Murray.; Mills, Barriss.; Mottram, Eric.; Newlove, John, 1938-; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970.; Olson, Toby.; Oppen, George.; Ossman, David.; Osterlund, Steven, 1943-; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975.; Phelps, Donald, 1929-; Quartermain, Peter.; Quasha, George.; Rackstraw, Richard, -1974.; Rothenberg, Jerome, 1931-; Royet-Journoud, Claude.; Schram, Irene, 1941-; Silliman, Ronald, 1946-; Smith, David, 1906-1965.; Smith, Welton.; Snyder, Gary.; Sobin, Gustaf.; Solomon, Stanley J.; Sorrentino, Gilbert.; Sward, Robert, 1933-; Taggart, John, 1942-; Tagliabue, John, 1923-; Tomlinson, Charles, 1927-2015.; Turnbull, Gael.; Vas Dias, Robert.; Wakoski, Diane.; Weightman, John, 1915-2004.; Weiner, Hannah.; Williams, Jonathan, 1929-2008.; Williams, Martin, 1924-1992.; Wilson, Keith, 1927-; Yaguchi, Yorifumi, 1932-; Zukofsky, Louis, 1904-1978.; Maps (Goshen, Ind.); American poetry -- 20th century.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Poets, American.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Editors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John Taggart, 1967-1971, 1973, 1975.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - American Literary Anthology, See Ardery, Peter
  - Ardery, Peter, 1967-1969; undated (Box 1)
  - Bayer, Herbert, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Bertholf, Robert J., 1974 (Box 1)
  - Blackburn, Paul, 1965; undated (Box 1)
  - Blackburn, Sara, undated (Box 1)
  - Blazek, Douglas, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Bly, Robert, 1966-1967; 1969,; undated (Box 1)
  - Boer, Charles, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Bowering, George, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Bronk, William, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Robert Edward, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Butterick, George F., 1969-1974 (Box 1)
  - Byrd, Bobby, 1966; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Carruth, Hayden, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Corman, Cid, 1967-1970; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Cornelius, Colin J., 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Cox, Kenneth, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Creeley, Robert, 1966-1967; 1972 (Box 1)
  - Davenport, Guy, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Davey, Frank, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Michael, 1974; undated (Box 1)
  - Duncan, Robert, 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - Economou, George, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Edson, Russell, 1965; 1966,; 1968 (Box 1)
  - Eigner, Larry, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
  - Emanuel, Pierre, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Enslin, Theodore, 1966-1970; 1972 (Box 1)
  - Eshleman, Clayton, 1965-1967; undated (Box 1)
  - Ferran, Jaime, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ferrini, Vincent, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Fowler, Gene, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Franks, David, 1968; undated (Box 1)
  - Fraser, Kathleen, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Galin Press, 1965-1967; undated (Box 1)
  - George, Jon, 1969; undated (Box 1)
  - Golden, Sean, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Goodell, Larry, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Grande, Felix, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Graves, Bradford, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Guest, Barbara, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Hall, Ted, 1969; undated (Box 1)
  - Heilig, Gabriel, 1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Heller, Michael, 1966-1974 (Box 1)
  - Irby, Kenneth, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Jenkins, Donald, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Ronald, 1972; 1974 (Box 1)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Kimberley, Nick, undated (Box 1)
  - Knox, Keith, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1972; undated (Box 1)
  - Kyger, Joanne, 1967 (Box 1)
  - La Belle, Christine, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Laughlin, James, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Lawhead Press, Inc., 1971 (Box 1)
  - Lekakis, Michael, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Lenfest, David, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Lewis, Harry, 1965 (Box 1)
  - MacIntyre, Wendy, 1973-1974; undated (Box 1)
  - Mac Low, Jackson, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - McNaughton, Duncan, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Mednick, Murray, undated (Box 1)
  - Mills, Barriss, 1965; undated (Box 1)
  - Mottram, Eric, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Newlove, John, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
  - Olson, Charles, undated (Box 2)
  - Olson, Toby, 1967-1969; undated (Box 2)
  - Oppen, George, 1967; undated (Box 2)
  - Ossman, David, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Osterlund, Steven, 1968-1970; undated (Box 2)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1972-1974 (Box 2)
  - Phelps, Donald, 1970; undated (Box 2)
  - Quartermain, Peter, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Quasha, George, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Rackstraw, Richard, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Richardson, Nelson, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Royet-Journoud, Claude, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Schicker, Stephen, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Schram, Irene, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Sedam, Malcolm, undated; ms. poems (Box 2)
  - Silliman, Ronald, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Welton, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Snyder, Gary, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Sobin, Gustaf, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Solomon, Stanley J., undated; ms. poems (Box 2)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Sward, Robert, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Tagliabue, John, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, 1966-1967; 1972 (Box 2)
  - Turnbull, Gael, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Vas Dias, Robert, 1965-1969; undated (Box 2)
  - Wakosi, Diane, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Weightman, John, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Weiner, Hannah, 1966-1967; undated (Box 2)
  - Williams, Jonathan, 1967-1973 (Box 2)
  - Williams, Martin T., 1968 (Box 2)
  - Wilson, Keith, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - Yaguchi, Yorifume, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - A-Z (Box 2)
  - First names, unidentified (Box 2)
- Memorabilia
  - Walt Whitman's Poems (with annotations by John Taggart) (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, flyer; clipping (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Maps (edited by John Taggart), miscellaneous notes; 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Maps #1
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 1 folder (Box 2)
        Paul Blackburn
        Russell Edson
        Clayton Eshleman
        Gabriel Heilig
        Kenneth Irby
        Welton Smith
        Robert Vas Dias
        Yorifumi Yaguchi
  - Maps #2
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 1 folder (Box 2)
        Douglas Blazek
        William Bronk
        Rene Char
        Larry Eigner
        Theodore Enslin
        Joanne Kyger
        John Newlove
        George Oppen
        Jerome Rothenberg
        Charles Tomlinson
        Hannah Weiner
      - Cover art, 1 folder (Box 2)
    - Production records
      - Galleys (Box 4)
  - Maps #3
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 1 folder (Box 2)
        Fernando Arbelaez
        J.G. Cobo-Borda
        George Economou
        Jaime Ferran
        Robert Foster
        David Franks
        Barbara Guest
        Ted Hall
        Michael Heller
        Robert Kelly
        Jackson Mac Low
        Toby Olson
        Steven Osterlund
        Stephanie Rowan
        John Taggart
      - Manuscripts, 2 folders (Box 3)
        Cid Corman
        Steven Schicker
      - Miscellany, 1 folder (Box 3)
    - Production records
      - Galleys (Box 4)
  - Maps #4
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 4 folders (Box 3)
        John Cech
        Vincent Ferrini
        David Melnick
        Charles Olson
        John Scoggan
      - Miscellany, 1 folder (Box 3)
    - Production records (Oversize 1)
  - Maps #5
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 2 folders (Box 3)
        Kenneth Cox
        Guy Davenport
        Jonathan Greene
        Hugh Kenner
        Eric Mottram
    - Production records
      - Galleys (Box 4)
  - Maps #6
    - Editorial files
      - Manuscripts, 3 folders (Box 3)
        Robert Duncan
        Ronald Johnson
        Ron Silliman
        Wendy MacIntyre
    - Production records
      - Galleys (Box 4)